Guide to the Whitman College Beta Theta Pi records 1911-2016
Whitman College and Northwest Archives
Whitman College Beta Theta Pi records
1911-2016
Whitman College and Northwest Archives 345 Boyer Avenue Walla Walla, WA 99362 Archives@whitman.edu https://library.whitman.edu/archives/
Beta Theta Pi. Gamma Zeta Chapter
WCA042
2.75 linear feet 5 boxes
The national fraternity, Beta Theta Pi, established the Whitman College Gamma Zeta chapter in 1914, and it has been a part of campus Greek life ever since. This collection consists of general records, publications, news articles, scrapbooks, ledgers, song books and manuals related to the social fraternity.
Collection is open for research.
Beta Theta Pi is a North American social fraternity founded in 1839 at Miami University in Oxford, Ohio. The Whitman College chapter originated as a local fraternity, Delta Phi Delta, in 1910. It was chartered as the Gamma Zeta Chapter of Beta Theta Pi in 1916, making it the second National Fraternity on campus. It is a member of the Miami Triad along with Sigma Chi and Phi Delta Theta (which have also established chapters on campus.) The group is the longest continuously operating fraternity at Whitman, and has several notable alumni, including actor Adam West and former Whitman College president, Chester Maxey, who helped charter the chapter.
The collection consists of general records, publications, news articles, scrapbooks, ledgers, song books and manuals related to Beta Theta Pi.
Whitman College--History; Greek letter societies
Colleges and Universities; Scrapbooks; Photographs
- 50th anniversary reunion recording, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 50th anniversary records, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Alumni relations, 1939-1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Annivesaries, 1969-1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Ben Flather's Award plaque, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- "The Code of Beta Theta Pi", 1930 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1930-1981 (Box 1, Folder 7-14)
- Dance and event programs, 1921-1959 (Box 1, Folder 15-18)
- Financial records, 1965, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- House records and floor plans, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Installation, 1914-1916 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Membership registers, 1940-1979 (Box 2, Folder 4-6)
- Newspaper articles, 1958-1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Officers and advisers, 1936, 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Minute book, 1916-1924 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- National magazine clippings, 1939-1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Membership register: Delta Phi Delta, 1909-1916 (Box 3, Object 1)
- Financial ledger, 1925-1953 (Box 3, Object 3)
- "The Great Ones," by A.J.G. Priest, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Beer stein, undated (Box 5, Object 1)
- Social events and promotional materials, 1929-2016 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Pins, circa 1920 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Publications, 1917-1992 (Box 2, Folder 12-19)
- Photographs, 1918-1990 (Box 2, Folder 20-27)
- "Son of the Stars" Beta Theta Pi pledge manual, 1942, 1962, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 29-31)
- "The Songs of Beta Theta Pi", 1912-1947, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 32-38)
- Scrapbook: Otto Anderson, class of 1927, 1923-1926 (Box 3, Object 2)
- Scrapbook: The Archives of the Beta Theta Pi, 1917-1934 (Box 4, Object 1)
- Photographs: Composites, 2001-2003, 2006-2007 (Box 4, Folder 1)